<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><metadata>
    <idinfo>
        <citation>
            <citeinfo>
                <origin/>
                <title>DC Streetcar Routes</title>
                <geoform>vector digital data</geoform>
            </citeinfo>
        </citation>
        <descript>
            <abstract>The District Department of Transportation (DDOT) launched DC Streetcar in February 2016 after more than 50 years. The rebirth of the streetcar emerged out of a mid-2000s planning effort to shape the future of transit in the city. The comprehensive District of Columbia Transit Improvements Alternatives Analysis  studied gaps in transit and identified ways to better meet the needs of residents. From there, DDOT focused on expanding transit service with the DC Circulator, express Metrobus routes, bus rapid transit, Capital Bike Share, and DC Streetcar. The streetcar offers an array of benefits. A fully envisioned streetcar system makes it easier for residents to move between neighborhoods and spurs economic development. Unlike buses, fixed rail lines attract long-term community investments in housing, retail, and commercial properties. </abstract>
            <purpose>Streetcars are passenger vehicles that operate on fixed rails on public streets.</purpose>
            <supplinf>The DC Circulator is all about downtown Washington, DC. Its five routes link cultural, entertainment and business destinations within the city's central core, and its buses featuring low floors, big windows, and multiple doors for easy on-and-off service are unlike any other public transit in town. The Circulator promotes ease of movement, encourages transit use and enhances existing public transportation systems, while also helping to reduce congestion and air pollution. The DC Cirulator is the product of a unique public/private partnership between the District Department of Transportation, Washington Metropolitan Area Transit Authority, and DC Surface Transit, Inc. The idea for a quick, efficient, low-cost public transit system originated in the National Capital Planning Commission's 1997 Extending the Legacy, and the Downtown Business Improvement District championed its implementation initially.</supplinf>
        </descript>
        <status>
            <progress>Complete</progress>
            <update>Annually</update>
        </status>
        <spdom>
            <bounding>
                <westbc>-77.004662</westbc>
                <eastbc>-76.969879</eastbc>
                <northbc>38.900306</northbc>
                <southbc>38.897773</southbc>
            </bounding>
        </spdom>
        <keywords>
            <theme>
                <themekt>None</themekt>
                <themekey>streetcar</themekey>
                <themekey>transit</themekey>
                <themekey>transportation</themekey>
            </theme>
            <theme>
                <themekt>ISO 19115 Topic Categories</themekt>
                <themekey>transportation</themekey>
            </theme>
            <place>
                <placekt>None</placekt>
                <placekey>washington dc</placekey>
                <placekey>district of columbia</placekey>
                <placekey>dc</placekey>
            </place>
        </keywords>
        <accconst>Other Constraints</accconst>
        <useconst>This work is licensed under a Creative Commons Attribution 4.0 International License.</useconst>
        <ptcontac>
            <cntinfo>
                <cntorgp>
                    <cntorg>District Department of Transportation</cntorg>
                </cntorgp>
                <cntpos>GIS and Applications Manager</cntpos>
                <cntaddr>
                    <addrtype>mailing</addrtype>
                    <address>250 M Street SE</address>
                    <city>Washington</city>
                    <state>DC</state>
                    <postal>20003</postal>
                </cntaddr>
                <cntvoice>(202) 673-6813</cntvoice>
                <cntemail>ddotgis@dc.gov</cntemail>
            </cntinfo>
        </ptcontac>
        <ptcontac>
            <cntinfo>
                <cntorgp>
                    <cntorg>Office of the Chief Technology Officer</cntorg>
                </cntorgp>
                <cntpos>GIS Data Coordinator</cntpos>
                <cntaddr>
                    <addrtype>mailing and physical</addrtype>
                    <address>200 I Street SE</address>
                    <city>Washington</city>
                    <state>DC</state>
                    <postal>20003</postal>
                    <country>US</country>
                </cntaddr>
                <cntvoice>(202) 727-2277</cntvoice>
                <cntemail>dcgis@dc.gov</cntemail>
                <hours>8:30 am - 5 pm</hours>
            </cntinfo>
        </ptcontac>
        <datacred>District Department of Transportation</datacred>
        <native>Version 6.2 (Build 9200) ; Esri ArcGIS 10.3.1.4959</native>
    </idinfo>
    <dataqual>
        <attracc>
            <attraccr>In process of validation by source and/or responsible agency</attraccr>
        </attracc>
        <logic>Validated by source and/or responsible agency</logic>
        <complete>Validated by source and/or responsible agency</complete>
        <lineage>
            <srcinfo>
                <srccite>
                    <citeinfo>
                        <pubdate>20100101</pubdate>
                        <title>DC Circulator Lines</title>
                    </citeinfo>
                </srccite>
                <typesrc>hardDisk</typesrc>
                <srccitea>DC Circulator Lines</srccitea>
                <srccontr>location and attribution</srccontr>
            </srcinfo>
            <procstep>
                <procdesc>Removed the Smithsonian/Mall route and moved the 7th St/Convention route and stops temporarily onto Maine Ave. This accounts for construction of the tennis stadium on the waterfront.</procdesc>
                <proccont>
                    <cntinfo>
                        <cntorgp>
                            <cntorg>Office of the Chief Technology Officer</cntorg>
                        </cntorgp>
                    </cntinfo>
                </proccont>
            </procstep>
            <procstep>
                <procdesc>Staff established a set up file for the Trimble's GeoXT GeoExplorer 2008 Series GPS unit prior to data collection. This file was populated in the field based on a circulator bus data dictionary created by DCGIS, which was then transferred to a personal geodatabase. Staff collected Bus Stop locations using the Trimble Units. The data was then transferred to the personal geodatabase which DCGIS staff reviewed, qc'd, and prepared for final publication.</procdesc>
                <procdate>20101228</procdate>
                <proccont>
                    <cntinfo>
                        <cntorgp>
                            <cntorg>Office of the Chief Technology Officer</cntorg>
                            <cntper>GIS Data Coordinator</cntper>
                        </cntorgp>
                        <cntaddr>
                            <addrtype>mailing and physical</addrtype>
                            <address>441 4th st NW, Suite 930 South</address>
                            <city>Washington</city>
                            <state>DC</state>
                            <postal>2001</postal>
                            <country>US</country>
                        </cntaddr>
                        <cntfax>202-727-5660</cntfax>
                        <cntemail>dcgis@dc.gov</cntemail>
                        <hours>9am - 5pm</hours>
                    </cntinfo>
                </proccont>
            </procstep>
            <procstep>
                <procdesc>Eastbound and Westbound Night lines were added to the GeorgeTown - Union Station line. 35 addtional (some duplicate) stops added for this night route as well.</procdesc>
                <procdate>20110107</procdate>
                <proccont>
                    <cntinfo>
                        <cntorgp>
                            <cntorg>OCTO</cntorg>
                        </cntorgp>
                    </cntinfo>
                </proccont>
            </procstep>
            <procstep>
                <procdesc>DDOT updated the Circulator Lines and stops for FY2012. - New Potomac Ave-Skyland route: Need shared stops (with 2 colors depicted) along 8th Street SE (8th and L, 8th and G, 8th and D (southbound)/E (northbound)). - New route: There are also two new stops being added in Anacostia (Howard Rd across from the Metro Station in both directions, and MLK Jr Ave and W (southbound)/between W and Pleasant (northbound)) - please see the attached pdf that shows the stops in this vicinity. - Union Station-Navy Yard route: Buses will be turning from Constitution north onto 2nd and making a loop by Columbus Plaza to F street and back down 2nd. The stops on Columbus Plaza and Louisiana Avenue will need to be removed from the layers. The one stop stop should be on Columbus Plaza at Massachusetts Ave (east side). - For McPherson Square there is a Woodley Park-McPherson Sq stop on 13th southbound before K, but the bus stops again on the south side of the square and again on 14th before heading north at K. - The Convention Center-SW Waterfront (orange) route is being suspended for now.</procdesc>
                <procdate>20110930</procdate>
                <proccont>
                    <cntinfo>
                        <cntorgp>
                            <cntorg>OCTO</cntorg>
                        </cntorgp>
                    </cntinfo>
                </proccont>
            </procstep>
            <procstep>
                <procdesc>1.) Reroute of Union Station-Navy Yard near Union Station to allow for shared stop with Union Station-Georgetown route Beginning October 1, 2012, Union Station-Navy Yard buses will detour westbound around Columbus Plaza, make a left on E Street NE, right on North Capitol Street, and right on Massachusetts Ave NE. The shared stop will be on eastbound Massachusetts Ave NE, just before E Street, where the current Union Station-Georgetown route stops now. A stop is also being added on westbound Massachusetts Avenue before Columbus Circle to allow those who wish to exit the bus before entering the Plaza to do so. Please note, Union Station-Georgetown route will proceed from that stop to the garage to layover. The Union Station-Navy Yard bus will proceed from this shared stop back towards the Navy Yard via 2nd Street on its normal routing. This change is necessitated by the fact that Columbus Plaza construction will eliminate the current Navy Yard route stop at the Thurgood Marshall Building in the fall 2012. 2.) Union Station-Navy Yard slight reroute at terminus At the southern terminus of the route, instead of turning right from 1st Street SE to I Street SE, buses will turn right from 1st Street SE to K Street SE. No bus stops will be impacted. Buses will continue on the normal route to the Navy Yard Metro stop and points north and east. 3.) Map change at 295 and Howard Rd The Circulator map will be updated to reflect current operations, whereby buses turn off of 295 onto Howard Rd directly, instead of using the clover leaf further to the south and looping back on Firth Sterling. No bus stops will be impacted.</procdesc>
                <procdate>20121007</procdate>
                <proccont>
                    <cntinfo>
                        <cntorgp>
                            <cntorg>OCTO</cntorg>
                        </cntorgp>
                    </cntinfo>
                </proccont>
            </procstep>
            <procstep>
                <procdesc>1. Stop to be added on MLK Ave SE: The address of the new stop is Good Hope Road and 13th St SE . It should be noted on the map BEFORE making the left turn onto MLK. The new stop should be on the right-hand (southbound) side of the street. 2. Stop to be added to Mass Ave NE: The new stop should be on the right-hand (Southbound) side of Mass Ave, just before the bus turns south on to 2nd St NE.</procdesc>
                <procdate>20131004</procdate>
                <proccont>
                    <cntinfo>
                        <cntorgp>
                            <cntorg>DDOT</cntorg>
                        </cntorgp>
                    </cntinfo>
                </proccont>
            </procstep>
        </lineage>
    </dataqual>
    <spdoinfo>
        <direct>Vector</direct>
        <ptvctinf>
            <sdtsterm>
                <sdtstype>Entity point</sdtstype>
                <ptvctcnt>12</ptvctcnt>
            </sdtsterm>
        </ptvctinf>
    </spdoinfo>
    <eainfo>
        <detailed>
            <enttyp>
                <enttypl>DCGIS.StreetCarPt</enttypl>
            </enttyp>
            <attr>
                <attrlabl>OBJECTID</attrlabl>
                <attrdef>Internal feature number.</attrdef>
                <attrdefs>ESRI</attrdefs>
                <attrdomv>
                                        					
                    
                    <udom>Sequential unique whole numbers that are automatically generated.</udom>
                                        				
                
                </attrdomv>
            </attr>
            <attr>
                <attrlabl>Shape</attrlabl>
                <attrdef>Feature geometry</attrdef>
                <attrdefs>ESRI</attrdefs>
                <attrdomv>
                                        					
                    
                    <udom>Coordinates defining the features.</udom>
                                        				
                
                </attrdomv>
            </attr>
            <attr>
                <attrlabl>SHAPE</attrlabl>
                <attrdef>Feature geometry.</attrdef>
                <attrdefs>ESRI</attrdefs>
                <attrdomv>
                                        					
                    
                    <udom>Coordinates defining the features.</udom>
                                        				
                
                </attrdomv>
            </attr>
            <attr>
                <attrlabl>Creator</attrlabl>
            </attr>
            <attr>
                <attrlabl>Created</attrlabl>
            </attr>
            <attr>
                <attrlabl>Editor</attrlabl>
            </attr>
            <attr>
                <attrlabl>YCOORD</attrlabl>
            </attr>
            <attr>
                <attrlabl>Edited</attrlabl>
            </attr>
            <attr>
                <attrlabl>STOPERROR</attrlabl>
            </attr>
            <attr>
                <attrlabl>STOPORDER</attrlabl>
            </attr>
            <attr>
                <attrlabl>LINE</attrlabl>
                <attrdef>DC Circulator Bus Line Name</attrdef>
                <attrdefs>ESRI</attrdefs>
                <attrdomv>
                                        					
                    
                    <udom>Coordinates defining the features.</udom>
                                        				
                
                </attrdomv>
            </attr>
            <attr>
                <attrlabl>STOP</attrlabl>
            </attr>
            <attr>
                <attrlabl>LINEID</attrlabl>
            </attr>
            <attr>
                <attrlabl>ATBUSSHELTER</attrlabl>
            </attr>
            <attr>
                <attrlabl>STOPSTATUS</attrlabl>
            </attr>
            <attr>
                <attrlabl>STATUSDESCRIPTION</attrlabl>
            </attr>
            <attr>
                <attrlabl>CREATED_USER</attrlabl>
            </attr>
            <attr>
                <attrlabl>CREATED_DATE</attrlabl>
            </attr>
            <attr>
                <attrlabl>LAST_EDITED_USER</attrlabl>
            </attr>
            <attr>
                <attrlabl>LAST_EDITED_DATE</attrlabl>
            </attr>
            <attr>
                <attrlabl>ADACOMPLIANT</attrlabl>
            </attr>
            <attr>
                <attrlabl>SHAREDSTOP</attrlabl>
            </attr>
            <attr>
                <attrlabl>STOPMEAS</attrlabl>
            </attr>
            <attr>
                <attrlabl>SE_ANNO_CAD_DATA</attrlabl>
            </attr>
            <attr>
                <attrlabl>GIS_ID</attrlabl>
            </attr>
            <attr>
                <attrlabl>GlobalID</attrlabl>
            </attr>
        </detailed>
    </eainfo>
    <metainfo>
        <metd>20230313</metd>
        <metc>
            <cntinfo>
                <cntorgp>
                    <cntorg>Office of the Chief Technology Officer</cntorg>
                </cntorgp>
                <cntpos>GIS Data Coordinator</cntpos>
                <cntaddr>
                    <addrtype>mailing and physical</addrtype>
                    <address>200 I Street SE, 5th Floor</address>
                    <city>Washington</city>
                    <state>DC</state>
                    <postal>20003</postal>
                    <country>US</country>
                </cntaddr>
                <cntvoice>(202) 727-2277</cntvoice>
                <cntfax>(202) 727-5660</cntfax>
                <cntemail>dcgis@dc.gov</cntemail>
                <hours>8:30 am - 5 pm</hours>
            </cntinfo>
        </metc>
        <metstdn>FGDC Content Standard for Digital Geospatial Metadata</metstdn>
        <metstdv>FGDC-STD-001-1998</metstdv>
        <mettc>local time</mettc>
    </metainfo>
</metadata>
