<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><metadata>
    <idinfo>
        <citation>
            <citeinfo>
                <origin/>
                <pubdate>20100401</pubdate>
                <title>Virginia Railway Express Routes</title>
                <geoform>Vector digital data</geoform>
                <lworkcit>
                    <citeinfo>
                        <pubdate>20100401</pubdate>
                        <title>NAVTEQ data, available for 81 countries on 6 continents, is organized into 4 categories of geospatial data layers and related tabular datasets including 1) Road Features and Associated Navigation Information, 2) Points of Interest (POIs), 3) Administrative Areas and Other Cartography, and 4) Metadata. These datasets include Streets, Major Highways, Secondary Highways, Signs, Driving Conditions, Traffic, Travel Destinations, Parking, Named Places, Auto Maintenance, Service, and Petrol, Hospitals, Restaurants, Shopping, Business Facilities, Entertainment, Financial Institutions, Educational Institutions, Transportation Hubs, Border Crossings, Parks and Recreation, Community Service Centres, Country, State, and other Administrative Areas, Buildings, Landmarks, Railroads, Land Use, Waterways, Islands, and Oceans, and other related information. NAVTEQ global map data includes approximately 19 million roadway miles (over 30.5 million kilometers) and over 40 million POIs in approximately 69 categories.</title>
                    </citeinfo>
                </lworkcit>
            </citeinfo>
        </citation>
        <descript>
            <abstract>The dataset contains locations and attributes of Virginia Railway Express (VRE) Routes, created as part of the DC Geographic Information System (DC GIS) for the Office of the Chief Technology Officer (OCTO) and participating D.C. government agencies. The data is extracted from NAVTEQ RAILRDS.</abstract>
            <purpose>This data is used for the planning and management of Washington, DC by local government agencies.</purpose>
            <supplinf>NAVTEQ maps provide a highly accurate representation of the detailed road network including hundreds of attributes such as turn restrictions, physical barriers and gates, one-way streets, restricted access and relative road heights. NAVTEQ digital map data offers accuracy, detail, reliability, and flexibility. Continuously updated to maintain its freshness and precision, NAVTEQ digital map data not only enables door-to-door routing it contains millions of Points of Interest (POIs), making it easy to locate everything from restaurants to hospitals and gas stations. NAVTEQ data are found onboard most navigation-enabled vehicles produced around the world and on all the top Internet navigation sites. It is the unseen force behind the leading express mail services, emergency and government routing plans, efficient field service management, as well as numerous fleet operations, worldwide. Plus, it is the foundation for a growing category of wireless, Location Based Services (LBS). NAVTEQ offers digital map coverage in 81 countries on 6 continents. In addition to widely used GIS formats, including ESRI and MapInfo, data are also available in a number of other formats including RDF (Relational Data Format), GDF (Geographic Data Format), SIF+ (Standard Interchange Format), POI XML, and ODF (Oracle Delivery Format). An in-depth description of NAVTEQ datasets, data processing methodology, geometry, attributes, and metadata is provided to NAVTEQ customers through the NAVSTREETS Reference Manual and a number of other supplemental documents. NAVTEQ documentation uses standardized British spelling.</supplinf>
        </descript>
        <timeperd>
            <timeinfo>
                <sngdate>
                    <caldate>20100401</caldate>
                </sngdate>
            </timeinfo>
            <current>Publication date</current>
        </timeperd>
        <status>
            <progress>Complete</progress>
            <update>As needed</update>
        </status>
        <spdom>
            <bounding>
                <westbc>-150.12742</westbc>
                <eastbc>-63.269759</eastbc>
                <northbc>64.926621</northbc>
                <southbc>14.67113</southbc>
            </bounding>
        </spdom>
        <keywords>
            <theme>
                <themekt>None</themekt>
                <themekey>vre</themekey>
                <themekey>Transportation</themekey>
                <themekey>railroad</themekey>
                <themekey>virginia railway express</themekey>
                <themekey>commuter</themekey>
            </theme>
            <theme>
                <themekt>ISO 19115 Topic Categories</themekt>
                <themekey>transportation</themekey>
            </theme>
            <place>
                <placekt>None</placekt>
                <placekey>Washington DC</placekey>
                <placekey>DC GIS</placekey>
                <placekey>District of Columbia</placekey>
                <placekey>virginia</placekey>
            </place>
        </keywords>
        <accconst>Other Constraints</accconst>
        <useconst>This work is licensed under a Creative Commons Attribution 4.0 International License.</useconst>
        <ptcontac>
            <cntinfo>
                <cntorgp>
                    <cntorg>NAVTEQ</cntorg>
                </cntorgp>
            </cntinfo>
        </ptcontac>
        <ptcontac>
            <cntinfo>
                <cntorgp>
                    <cntorg>Office of the Chief Technology Officer</cntorg>
                    <cntper>GIS Data Coordinator</cntper>
                </cntorgp>
                <cntaddr>
                    <addrtype>mailing and physical</addrtype>
                    <address>200 I Street SE, 5th Floor</address>
                    <city>Washington</city>
                    <state>DC</state>
                    <postal>20003</postal>
                    <country>US</country>
                </cntaddr>
                <cntvoice>(202) 727-2277</cntvoice>
                <cntfax>(202) 727-6857</cntfax>
                <cntemail>dcgis@dc.gov</cntemail>
                <hours>8:30 am - 5 pm</hours>
            </cntinfo>
        </ptcontac>
        <datacred>NAVTEQ incorporates and enhances data from a number of local governments, utility companies, other public agencies, and commercial mapping agencies in building its final products.</datacred>
        <native>Version 6.2 (Build 9200) ; Esri ArcGIS 10.5.1.7333</native>
        <crossref>
            <citeinfo>
                <pubdate>20100401</pubdate>
                <title>NAVTEQ data, available for 81 countries on 6 continents, is organized into 4 categories of geospatial data layers and related tabular datasets including 1) Road Features and Associated Navigation Information, 2) Points of Interest (POIs), 3) Administrative Areas and Other Cartography, and 4) Metadata. These datasets include Streets, Major Highways, Secondary Highways, Signs, Driving Conditions, Traffic, Travel Destinations, Parking, Named Places, Auto Maintenance, Service, and Petrol, Hospitals, Restaurants, Shopping, Business Facilities, Entertainment, Financial Institutions, Educational Institutions, Transportation Hubs, Border Crossings, Parks and Recreation, Community Service Centres, Country, State, and other Administrative Areas, Buildings, Landmarks, Railroads, Land Use, Waterways, Islands, and Oceans, and other related information. NAVTEQ global map data includes approximately 19 million roadway miles (over 30.5 million kilometers) and over 40 million POIs in approximately 69 categories.</title>
            </citeinfo>
        </crossref>
    </idinfo>
    <dataqual>
        <attracc>
            <attraccr>NAVTEQ field office staff drives the roads and streets to collect and verify new data, and then drives them over again to confirm the accuracy of all information contained in the database. In addition, internal test applications are regularly run on attributes to assist in verification and correction. NAVTEQ also publishes Technical Notification Memorandums (TNM) for customers on a quarterly basis. These TNMs include information pertaining to product updates, format changes, new attributes, detailed attribute specifications and representations, and new country coverage announcements. If NAVTEQ plans to add, remove, or change an attribute or product feature, an announcement is made to customers a minimum of 6 months in advance. This allows customers to prepare and make necessary modifications to their applications before a new attribute is released in the core product.</attraccr>
        </attracc>
        <logic>NAVTEQ data contains the most navigable attributes available in a database. Utilizing the data to its fullest allows the user to access features such as expressway ramps, complete and correct connectivity of all roadways, one-way streets, physical, logical, and legal turn restrictions, construction projects, as well as physical and painted lane dividers. In addition to these navigable attributes, NAVTEQ data provides address ranges down to the level of the correct side of the street.</logic>
        <complete>NAVTEQ provides 4 levels of street map coverage: Prime/Detailed City, Network/Inter-Town, Road Network/Complete and Major Road Network/City to City. Prime/Detailed City is NAVTEQ's highest level of coverage. This coverage level has the most detail and enables door-to-door routing functionality. Network/Inter-Town coverage includes the main highway network and all the necessary attributes required to allow routing from city to city. Network/Inter-Town links are coded with attributes Detailed City Inclusion = N and In-Process Data = N. For Network/Inter-town links, the Full Geometry attribute flag may be set to either yes or no depending on the presence or lack of surrounding In-Process Data Coverage. In many countries, NAVTEQ has used a commercial source to add local roads to the Inter-Town network. The inclusion of this geometry allows improved map display and guidance. This coverage level is called Complete in the U.S. and Road Network Coverage in Europe. The Connector Specification enables NAVTEQ to maintain minimum coverage in areas prior to completing (full) Prime/Detailed City (DC), Network/Inter Town (IT), or In-Process areas. For defining a hierarchical network used to determine a logical and efficient route for a traveler, each NAVTEQ street segment is tagged with a 5 level Functional Class (FC) attribute explained as follows. FC 1: Very long distance routes between major cities - The "highest level" network comprises the FC 1 arterials, which are primarily controlled access highways designed for very-long-distance travel linking major metropolitan areas and cities, FC 2: Primary routes between major and smaller cities and through metro areas, FC 3: Major routes between minor cities or towns, and through city districts, FC 4: Routes connecting minor towns or villages and collecting the local traffic in the city districts, and FC 5: Roads that are not efficient through routes - The "lowest level" and final category is FC 5, which comprises roads not considered to be arterials or transportation corridors.</complete>
        <posacc>
            <horizpa>
                <horizpar>Boundaries for cartographic features may be generalized. Generalisation refers to the process of reusing existing links when cartography and administrative boundaries are created. If existing geometry is within the generalization guidelines below, then the feature is added to the existing links instead of creating additional geometry. Roads and ferries cannot share geometry with railways, runways, country boundaries, or any water links. Additionally, Building/Landmark polygons which require sufficient detail to make the building recognisable, can never share geometry with navigable links. All other cartography may share geometry based on the generalisation rules. For example, a road link or railroad link may also have a feature of state park or hospital. Cartography and administrative boundary features in Detailed City areas can be generalised up to 25 metres/82 feet (except built-up areas) and 100 metres/328 feet for built-up areas Cartography and administrative boundary features in Inter-Town areas can be eneralised up to 250 metres/820 feet (except built-up areas) 100 metres/328 feet for built-up areas.</horizpar>
            </horizpa>
        </posacc>
        <lineage>
            <procstep>
                <procdesc>NAVTEQ's comprehensive data build process ensures the highest quality data available for routing and mapping applications. The process begins with establishing a field office in the new build area. Source or Base Maps are acquired from a variety of sources including local governments, utility companies, other public agencies, and commercial mapping agencies. These maps are then carefully reviewed and digitized. All base map data is further enhanced with aerial photos and differential GPS to accurately position roads and represent lakes, rivers, railroads, etc., and proprietary software is then used to add navigable information, addresses, and points of interest. NAVTEQ additionally road tests the data to further add to the quality of the database. Field office staff drives the roads and streets to collect and verify new data, and then drives them over again to confirm the accuracy of all information contained in the database. Photographs are also taken of all overhead signage to ensure that the data accurately reflects the real world.</procdesc>
                <proccont>
                    <cntinfo>
                        <!--no contact person or organization name available-->
                        <cntaddr>
                            <addrtype>unknown</addrtype>
                            <address>200 I Street SE, 5th Floor</address>
                        </cntaddr>
                    </cntinfo>
                </proccont>
            </procstep>
            <procstep>
                <procdesc>Source acquisition: The process begins with establishing a field office in the new build area. Source or Base Maps are acquired from a variety of sources including local governments, utility companies, other public agencies, and commercial mapping agencies. These sources of information, in the form of maps, charts, and imagery, provide the basic roadway detail for the new build area.</procdesc>
                <proccont>
                    <cntinfo>
                        <!--no contact person or organization name available-->
                        <cntaddr>
                            <addrtype>unknown</addrtype>
                            <address>200 I Street SE, 5th Floor</address>
                        </cntaddr>
                    </cntinfo>
                </proccont>
            </procstep>
            <procstep>
                <procdesc>Data validation: NAVTEQ subjects the data to hundreds of automated validation tests to provide accuracy. These tests are complemented by regular reports from the field teams, who periodically re-drive the roads and streets to collect and verify new data, and confirm the accuracy of all information contained in the database.</procdesc>
                <proccont>
                    <cntinfo>
                        <!--no contact person or organization name available-->
                        <cntaddr>
                            <addrtype>unknown</addrtype>
                            <address>200 I Street SE, 5th Floor</address>
                        </cntaddr>
                    </cntinfo>
                </proccont>
            </procstep>
            <procstep>
                <procdesc>The NAVTEQ data production environment, while not designed to be adopted directly by customers, is designed to insulate customers from data structure changes, additions, and deletions. NAVTEQ uses data extraction formats to "publish" NAVTEQ data externally to its customers, enabling them to process map data into their own production environment. These extraction formats generally have a design that is independent from the NAVTEQ internal production environment, and are not impacted when NAVTEQ modifies parts of the production environment. Extraction formats generally publish the same content, with differences only in the representation of the data.</procdesc>
                <proccont>
                    <cntinfo>
                        <!--no contact person or organization name available-->
                        <cntaddr>
                            <addrtype>unknown</addrtype>
                            <address>200 I Street SE, 5th Floor</address>
                        </cntaddr>
                    </cntinfo>
                </proccont>
            </procstep>
            <procstep>
                <procdesc>Geometry development: NAVTEQ verifies (and if needed, corrects) the data by bringing together the source material, field data gathered through driving the road network, and additional digital imagery. All base map data is further enhanced with aerial photos and differential GPS to accurately position roads and represent lakes, rivers, railroads, etc.</procdesc>
                <proccont>
                    <cntinfo>
                        <!--no contact person or organization name available-->
                        <cntaddr>
                            <addrtype>unknown</addrtype>
                            <address>200 I Street SE, 5th Floor</address>
                        </cntaddr>
                    </cntinfo>
                </proccont>
            </procstep>
            <procstep>
                <procdesc>Geocoding: The field and production teams code the one-ways, no-turns, postal codes, and other details to every location on the map.</procdesc>
                <proccont>
                    <cntinfo>
                        <!--no contact person or organization name available-->
                        <cntaddr>
                            <addrtype>unknown</addrtype>
                            <address>200 I Street SE, 5th Floor</address>
                        </cntaddr>
                    </cntinfo>
                </proccont>
            </procstep>
            <procstep>
                <procdesc>Field data collection: Using proprietary tools and processes, NAVTEQ collects everything from road geometry to road attributes, 260 in all, on roads, streets, and highways throughout the world. Proprietary software is used to add navigable information, addresses, and points of interest. All overhead signage is collected to ensure that the data accurately reflects the real world.</procdesc>
                <proccont>
                    <cntinfo>
                        <!--no contact person or organization name available-->
                        <cntaddr>
                            <addrtype>unknown</addrtype>
                            <address>200 I Street SE, 5th Floor</address>
                        </cntaddr>
                    </cntinfo>
                </proccont>
            </procstep>
            <procstep>
                <procdesc>Source normalization: Source maps are carefully reviewed and digitized. The data are normalized and entered into the NAVTEQ database.</procdesc>
                <proccont>
                    <cntinfo>
                        <!--no contact person or organization name available-->
                        <cntaddr>
                            <addrtype>unknown</addrtype>
                            <address>200 I Street SE, 5th Floor</address>
                        </cntaddr>
                    </cntinfo>
                </proccont>
            </procstep>
            <procstep>
                <procdesc>NAVTEQ SDC data layers are generated through the use of an external 3rd party application, which converts and merges multiple NAVSTREETS ShapeFiles and tabular navigation data tables for North America into single SDC layers and supporting file sets.</procdesc>
                <proccont>
                    <cntinfo>
                        <!--no contact person or organization name available-->
                        <cntaddr>
                            <addrtype>unknown</addrtype>
                            <address>200 I Street SE, 5th Floor</address>
                        </cntaddr>
                    </cntinfo>
                </proccont>
            </procstep>
            <procstep>
                <procdesc>NAVTEQ uses a six-step production process to build its digital road maps: source acquisition, source normalization, geometry development, field data collection, geocoding, and data validation. These steps involve compiling maps, charts and imagery, driving the road network, developing proprietary tools and processes, using hundreds of automated validation tests, and periodically re-driving the roads to ensure the data are as up-to-date as possible.</procdesc>
                <proccont>
                    <cntinfo>
                        <!--no contact person or organization name available-->
                        <cntaddr>
                            <addrtype>unknown</addrtype>
                            <address>200 I Street SE, 5th Floor</address>
                        </cntaddr>
                    </cntinfo>
                </proccont>
            </procstep>
            <procstep>
                <procdesc>NAVTEQ digital map data is built on the roads of the world. Over one thousand NAVTEQ field researchers from approximately 203 offices drive millions of kilometers of the road network each year. To provide uniformity and maximize precision each team works to a single global specification. And each team has state-of-the-art equipment, including our proprietary GPS-based collection technology and software.</procdesc>
                <proccont>
                    <cntinfo>
                        <!--no contact person or organization name available-->
                        <cntaddr>
                            <addrtype>unknown</addrtype>
                            <address>200 I Street SE, 5th Floor</address>
                        </cntaddr>
                    </cntinfo>
                </proccont>
            </procstep>
            <procstep>
                <procdesc>NAVTEQ Data users can help maintain and improve data accuracy by reporting suggested changes to NAVTEQ. Map updates can be submitted through the web based Map Reporter application at http://mapreporter.navteq.com/dur-web-external/. The status of updates can also be checked at this website after submittals.</procdesc>
                <proccont>
                    <cntinfo>
                        <!--no contact person or organization name available-->
                        <cntaddr>
                            <addrtype>unknown</addrtype>
                            <address>200 I Street SE, 5th Floor</address>
                        </cntaddr>
                    </cntinfo>
                </proccont>
            </procstep>
            <procstep>
                <procdesc>Added Spotsylvania Route</procdesc>
                <procdate>20220909</procdate>
            </procstep>
        </lineage>
    </dataqual>
    <spdoinfo>
        <direct>Vector</direct>
        <ptvctinf>
            <sdtsterm>
                <sdtstype>String</sdtstype>
                <ptvctcnt>2</ptvctcnt>
            </sdtsterm>
        </ptvctinf>
    </spdoinfo>
    <eainfo>
        <detailed>
            <enttyp>
                <enttypl>DCGIS.VRE_Lines</enttypl>
                <enttypd>Railroads - The RAILRDS layer contains Railroad features represented as lines and polylines. Attributes for this layer include the name of the railroad, and values indicating if the railroad goes onto a bridge or through a tunnel. This layer is used primarily for map visualisation.</enttypd>
                <enttypds>NAVTEQ</enttypds>
            </enttyp>
            <attr>
                <attrlabl>OBJECTID</attrlabl>
                <attrdef>Internal feature number.</attrdef>
                <attrdefs>ESRI</attrdefs>
                <attrdomv>
                                        					
                    
                    <udom>Sequential unique whole numbers that are automatically generated.</udom>
                                        				
                
                </attrdomv>
            </attr>
            <attr>
                <attrlabl>RAILWAY_NM</attrlabl>
                <attrdef>Railway Name - The Railway Name is equivalent to the Feature Name. The base name of the feature. It is a numbered route, local name, or a commonly accepted name for a feature.</attrdef>
                <attrdefs>NAVTEQ</attrdefs>
                <attrdomv>
                                        					
                    
                    <udom>The set of all RAILWAY_NM values</udom>
                                        				
                
                </attrdomv>
            </attr>
            <attr>
                <attrlabl>SHAPE</attrlabl>
                <attrdef>Shape Points - Sets of binary spatial coordinate values representing ESRI geometry objects as Points, Polylines, or Polygons.</attrdef>
                <attrdefs>NAVTEQ</attrdefs>
                <attrdomv>
                                        					
                    
                    <udom>The set of all geometry object values.</udom>
                                        				
                
                </attrdomv>
            </attr>
            <attr>
                <attrlabl>SE_ANNO_CAD_DATA</attrlabl>
            </attr>
            <attr>
                <attrlabl>GIS_ID</attrlabl>
            </attr>
            <attr>
                <attrlabl>GlobalID</attrlabl>
            </attr>
            <attr>
                <attrlabl>Creator</attrlabl>
            </attr>
            <attr>
                <attrlabl>Created</attrlabl>
            </attr>
            <attr>
                <attrlabl>Editor</attrlabl>
            </attr>
            <attr>
                <attrlabl>Edited</attrlabl>
            </attr>
            <attr>
                <attrlabl>SHAPE.LEN</attrlabl>
            </attr>
        </detailed>
    </eainfo>
    <distinfo>
        <distrib>
            <cntinfo>
                <cntorgp>
                    <cntorg>Office of the Chief Technology Officer</cntorg>
                    <cntper>GIS Data Coordinator</cntper>
                </cntorgp>
                <cntaddr>
                    <addrtype>mailing and physical</addrtype>
                    <address>200 I Street SE, 5th Floor</address>
                    <city>Washington</city>
                    <state>DC</state>
                    <postal>20003</postal>
                    <country>US</country>
                </cntaddr>
                <cntvoice>(202) 727-2277</cntvoice>
                <cntfax>(202) 727-6857</cntfax>
                <cntemail>dcgis@dc.gov</cntemail>
                <hours>8:30 am - 5 pm</hours>
            </cntinfo>
        </distrib>
        <distliab>See access and use constraints information.</distliab>
        <custom>DC datasets can be downloaded from "http://opendata.dc.gov".</custom>
    </distinfo>
    <metainfo>
        <metd>20220907</metd>
        <metc>
            <cntinfo>
                <cntorgp>
                    <cntorg>Office of the Chief Technology Officer</cntorg>
                    <cntper>GIS Data Coordinator</cntper>
                </cntorgp>
                <cntaddr>
                    <addrtype>mailing and physical</addrtype>
                    <address>200 I Street SE, 5th Floor</address>
                    <city>Washington</city>
                    <state>DC</state>
                    <postal>20003</postal>
                    <country>US</country>
                </cntaddr>
                <cntvoice>(202) 727-2277</cntvoice>
                <cntfax>(202) 727-6857</cntfax>
                <cntemail>dcgis@dc.gov</cntemail>
                <hours>8:30 am - 5 pm</hours>
            </cntinfo>
        </metc>
        <metstdn>FGDC Content Standard for Digital Geospatial Metadata</metstdn>
        <metstdv>FGDC-STD-001-1998</metstdv>
        <mettc>local time</mettc>
    </metainfo>
</metadata>
